Listen, if you are an online coach or
mentor, getting your pricing right is
one of the most important things that
you can do. On this episode of the Grow
Your Life podcast, I'm going to break
down pricing strategy that's going to
work for you. I've been building online
coaching, mentorship, training,
consulting businesses for the last 22
years. And every single day, I work with
my clients in my wealthy coach academy
program to show them exactly step by
step what to do to get more clients, get
more leads, and ultimately make multiple
six and even seven figures in their
businesses. For those of you that I have
not met yet, thanks for being here. And
we have tons of episodes of this
podcast, the Grow Your Life podcast,
both on our YouTube channel and on
podcasting platforms that you can check
out. I also post weekly videos on
YouTube that are not part of the
podcast. They're just training videos
that you can watch that are absolutely
free on my YouTube channel. So, make
sure to go check those out as well. Now,
when it comes to pricing, first off,
it's important to get it right. The
problem that I see a lot of coaches do
is they either overpric or underpric
what they're doing. If you're
underpricing, people aren't going to
take you seriously. And here's the big
kicker, you're not going to make enough
profit. You're not going to make enough
money to be able to actually sustain
your business. You're going to get burnt
out. However, if you overpric, nobody's
going to buy from you. And so sometimes
I've seen people create different
offers, but they price it in a way that
is actually not going to work for them
depending on what the offer is. When it
comes to different offers, we split it
out into two different categories. We
have our programs, okay?
And then we have our
leadin
products. And so a leadin product can
even be free. However, we're noticing
that if you attach just a small price
tag to it, like $4.95,
that price tag actually
deters people that are not serious about
taking action away from your program.
And listen, it can become really
addicting to say, "I got a lot of
numbers. cuz I got thousands of leads
and things like that, but if they're not
converting to sales into your paid
program, it's ultimately not going to
help you. Now, you're not going to make
six figures on 495 products. In fact,
you're hardly going to even break even
on that. What this does is this is what
qualifies the person who's going to end
up joining your programs. Now, different
there's different price points for
programs that I've seen. And what I like
to do is I like to break it down monthly
and then extend that out by at least 12
months. What is that 12 month factor add
up to? So, I've seen programs for I
would say the minimum that you should
probably do for a program is $47 a
month. I've seen some people do $27 a
month for a program for me. Um, but the
problem is is that again, you don't make
enough profit to be able to sustain
that. $47 a month, you're going to be
making
right around well, give or take $7* 36.
You're going to be making right around
five 500 I don't I don't do like quick
math very well. I'm sure some of youall
are better at this. Right around $570 a
year off of this. Okay. And so this is
that's enough to be able to make a
profit with a program on. Now, it's not
a lot of profit, but it's enough that
it's going to sustain things for you in
your business and the amount of people
that you're going to get. Now, I also
like to price programs out to where
maybe they are $2,000 a year or
$10,000 a year. Now, what determines if
we're going to be doing a $2,000 a year
program, a $10,000 a year program, or a
$500 a year program? Well,
what determines it is how many people
you want to get in and who you want to
qualify. So, pricing is a qualification
factor. It's a boundary on what you
offer. And so the more you charge, the
less people are going to come in, but
also they're going to be more qualified
and less headaches for who is actually
coming in to a qualified program like
that. And so I want you to consider that
as well with your price point. And you
could break this down to, you know,
$800 to $900 a month if you do do the
math on that. What's 800 *
12? 8 * 12 is 96. So you we're right
under
$10,000 right there. $9,600 at $800 a
month. Okay.
If you go $2,000, you're looking at
right around
$166 to $197 a month. And these are
monthly charges for programs that you
can do. You can even charge weekly on
this.
And at those different price points, $47
a month. Yeah. You can even do $97 a
month.
You're going to be able to make enough
money that's going to sustain and build
your business and have recurring revenue
with a membership that does this. Now,
you might be saying, "Well, what am I
going to offer monthly with that?" Well,
again, it's access to your training.
It's access to coaching with you. It's
access to resources that people get. And
you don't have need to have them all
built before you launch something like
this, but you do want to make sure that
you get your pricing right. So, this is
the price points that we actually see
that are working really well for most
people that are just starting out and
they want to get into group coaching.
Again, I like a $4.95 leadin offer,
$4.95.
And then I like $47 to $97 a month. Now,
if you're more experienced, you already
have a membership, I want you to raise
your prices. I want you to bump them up
to at least $150 to $197 a month. Get to
that point. I would still do a 495 lead
in. I think that that's great as far as
that goes. And then consider adding a
high ticket program
on top of it for $800 to $900 a month.
And what this is is this is an elite
program that people can upgrade from
this level into this program to get more
access with you, more commitment, and
ultimately this is going to help you
with your profit margins. If you have
these programs built out this way and
you offer that to people and you have a
leadin offer that's $4.95, you can
sustainably build a business to seven
figures. We actually use this exact
model to build a music coaching business
to over a million dollars per month in
people that were coming in recurring
revenue. We would actually do we we
would actually have over a hundred
people per month that were doing this uh
$1,000 level right here. And then we
would have multiple different levels of
people that were coming in on these
other levels and and and all of this
added up to being over a million dollars
a month, which is incredible to be able
to create. It was sustainable. It was it
was amazing. Now, there was other stuff
as far as investments and things like
that that were going on that were that
sustained that million dollar a month,
but just from the coaching business
alone, it did right around uh $400,000 a
month. about between $400 and $600,000 a
month. And so combined,
building a business like that to a
million dollar a month is absolutely
doable when you follow price points like
this. Now, for most of you, you're not
at the million dollar a month. You're
getting started. Okay? So, if you're
just getting started, again,
you got to keep things profitable. And
what's amazing is by doing an offer
that's $4.95 with a leadin, that gives
you enough that you can run advertising.
it pays for part of your advertising
and then your program because the people
are qualified that come in from that are
are going to end up being your profit
margins. Now, one thing that I will say
long-term, it's hard to be able to
create the kind of sustainable profit
that you want on just a $47 program on
just even a $197 program. So, adding
high ticket offers in there helps you
expand your profit margins into that.
Now, here's why I tell people this. You
hear all these different programs. This
is why you need to learn how to
streamline creating the content for your
program so that you're not taking all
this time and effort and energy and
hours and hours and hours to create all
of this content for people in your
programs. All of this stuff that you're
doing. I have two kids
and I spend a lot of time with those
kids and I'm not working all day long. I
utilize pricing like this and my
programs to be able to build a
sevenfigure coaching business that I get
to work from home. I get to invest when
I want to and I get to create the kind
of lifestyle that I wanted to all along
by doing this. And so if I was just
starting out today, these are actually
kind of the price points I would look at
for most people about the four $4.95
leadin offer. I'm I'm actually leaning
towards doing that more than you doing a
free lead magnet anymore. And so, like,
think about that. Free lead magnets,
especially if you're running
advertising, you know, you're losing
money each lead that you get, whereas
you can make back a little bit of that,
plus you're qualifying people better.
It's a win-win on on multiple fronts for
this. And the algorithm prefers paid
offers that are a little cheap. It's
cheap because if you charge more than
that, you're not going to actually make
more margins. it's just going to cost
you more in ad spend. Like if you
charged $100, it still might cost you
$200 to get somebody to register. If you
charge $5 though, you might only cost
you $10 to get somebody to register.
Now, you might be saying, "Well, I'm
still losing $5." Yeah, but you make
that then on the back end of this
because for every three people that sign
up for that, three to four people, you
can get somebody to sign up at $47 a
month, at $197 a month, and you'll make
your profit margins on top of that.
Okay, so this is what I think is best
for price points and what you can learn
from this. Now, here's the other thing,
too. Don't be afraid to change your
prices. Don't be afraid to adjust them.
A lot of times when it comes to price
points, we're afraid to make adjustments
because we don't know how people are
going to respond. Instead, it's better
to adjust it and then let the
marketplace
settle out so that then people realize,
okay, that's what the new price point is
going to be. and give people an
opportunity to sign up the old price
point and then raise your prices. Don't
be the cheapest option on the on the
market. I still think a low ticket lead
in offer is good. I think it's actually
a really good thing, but don't be afraid
to raise your prices over here and
that's going to help you make more
profit as well on people. All right,
listen. If you're a coach or mentor, I'd
love to work with you in my wealthy
coach academy program. You can try it
out for 14 days. Check it out, see if
it's for you. go through all the
trainings. We got bonus trainings. We
have an AI version of me that you can
communicate with inside of my program
that you can talk to, ask questions 247.
I'm in there personally as well, not my
AI, me personally in our Facebook group
that responding,
reviewing your sales copy, reviewing
your messaging, your ads, and all of
that to help you get results in your
business. This truly is a program where
I personally come alongside you and walk
you through every step of getting the
results that you want in your business.
And I'd love to help you and work with
you with that. Click one of the links in
the description below and that will go
through the sequence of how to get into
our program. All right, we'll talk soon.
Have a good one.
[Music]
[Applause]